

#### PERSONALSUMMARY

I have a strong interest in creating and developing applications, need oriented, in terms of user experience and problem solving using logic and algorithms, have a strong character and team player with excellent communication skills, and high self- motivation, multitasking, negotiation and problem solving skills using logic and algorithms.

# KEYCOMPETENCIES

A. Skill

- · Aplication Management
- · Aplication Development
- · Aplication Design
- · Business Analytics
- · Communication & Partnership
- · Software Development Life Cycle
- · Leadership & Organized
- · Campaign/Event Management
- · Digital Strategy
- · Community Management
- · Operations Management

## B. Tools and programming Language

#### Frontend

JavaScript, Node.js React JS ,Next.js, Axios, Next Js, Jquery, HTML, CSS,Bootsrapt

## Backend

Node Js ,PHP, Codeigniter,Java Spring Bot , Python, Laravel,Laravel Lumen (API) ,Soap Wsdl,Web service Rest Full API (JSON dan XML)

# Database

Mysql,Sql Server ,MariaDB ,Postgresql ,Ms .Access, Oracle

# **WORK HISTORY**

FullStack Developer

# PT. MNC SEKURITAS - MNC GROUP (Nov 2022 - Current)

- Creating an Integrated Account Opening System with BANK (CIMBS, BCA, SINARMAS) for RDN (Customer Fund Account) account opening, This application development also starts from the backend front end.
- Testing the application before use in the SIT (System Integration Testing) process, and then continue with UAT,
- Deployment on dev servers to ensure dev and semi-prod processes can run.
- Check the data transactions and fields needed for the RDN account opening integration process between middleware apps and the OPENING ACCOUNT system.
- -Testing and checking the entire application from the frontend and backend before going to the production server.
- Create data integration in the middleware support site application
- Add auto translate feature for every page, on company profile website
- Create and design a frontend application for event trading

## **Completed application project**

https://oa.mncsekuritas.id https://www.motiontrade.id

## Full stack developer

# PT VALDO INTERNATIONAL (Jan 2022 - November 2022.)

- Create and develop applications, including database design, triggers, and tables
- · Fill in the timeline and activities during the development process
- · Re-analyze the application design to match the documents requested from the client / user
- · Test the implementation of the feasibility of the system
- · Coordination of penetration testing by Qa regarding the application is made
- · Load process with the user and project manager regarding the results of the application development that was made
- · Receive the results of the application user testing documentation from
- if there are development changes and do not match the request from the system that has been in development
- · Make configuration deploy application configuration to the server
- · Create application documentation that is done

# Completed application project

- A .Loan and credit card data entry applications (Domain can only be accessed locally)
- B. Bank Danamon Host to Host Collection Desk Application (Domain can only be accessed locally)
- C .API integration with bank bri Finance (Domain can only be accessed locally)
- D. Develop Customer Service application (Domain can only be accessed locally)

### **Mobile Development**

Flutter Mobile React Native

#### **Operating System (OS)**

Windows Linux Mac - OS

### Other

VB . NET Sysadmin Git (Github / Gitlab) WordPress Prestashop

# Grapichs design:

Corel Draw Photo shop Canva

## **AWARDS RECEIVED**

YPTP - Scholarships (2017-2019) Ekasakti - IT Clinic based on business and Entrepreneurship (2018-2019)

#### **EDUCATION**

**DIPLOMA III** 

Ekasakti of University - Informatics and computer management (Graduated)

### **BACHELOR DEGREE**

Indraprasta of University - Technical Information (Under graduate)

### ORGANIZATION HISTORY

Member of Hima - informatics and computer management University of Ekasakti (2018 - 2019)

Head of IT - Clinic Informatics and computer management study program (2017 - 2019)

Administrator of campus da'wah institutions - Ekasakti University (2018 - 2019)

## **CONTACT INFORMATION:**

Email: ismarianto97@gmail.com

Phone : **0831-8230-5714** 

Linkedin : linkedin.com/in/isma-rianto-58250023b

My website : https://ismarianto.vercel.app

Instagram: @ismariantorian

Facebook : https://facebook.com/Ramoxzyass

Github : @ismarianto12 Address : West Jakarta Full stack developer

# PT BANK PANIN DUBAI SYARIAH . TBK (DESC 2020 - 2021)

- Create functionality and business requirements document application (FSD) Meeting time and coordinating with the project manager whether the fsd document created is suitable for the application development stage
- Create a timeline and flow activities that run from the application to be made Create a database, determine the schema table, relations, and triggers needed by the application development process, Save and create a repository in gitlab local
- Fill in the timeline and activities during the development process
   Re-analyze the application design to match the documents requested from the user
- Test the implementation of the feasibility of the system Coordination of penetration testing by qa regarding the application is made Load process with the user and project manager regarding the results of the application development that was made.
- Receive the results of the application user testing documentation from the user, if there are development changes and do not match the request from the system that has been in development
- Prepare for deployment by describing the deployment requirements of the application, for example, database version, programming language, server, and disk capacity required to the infrastructure and network team
- Documenting application flow

#### **Completed application project**

- A. CFOS (Customer Financing mortagage system) Domain can only be accessed locally
- B. Tazam (Tabungan Zam zam)

  Domain can only be accessed locally
- Hopes
   Domain can only be accessed locally

## Full stack developer

# BADAN PENDAPATAN DAERAH TANGERANG SELATAN (DESC 2019 - 2020)

Create a timeline and flow activities that run from the application to be made

Create a database, determine the schema table, relations, and triggers needed by the application development process

Fill in the timeline and activities during the development process

Re-analyze the application design to match the documents requested from the user

Test the implementation of the feasibility of the system

Coordination of penetration testing by qa regarding the application is made

Load process with the user and project manager regarding the results of the application development that was made

Deploy application configuration to server

Documenting application flow

#### **SCAN ME**



#### Completed application project

A. Sakila (One-Click Service) tax and licensing of the south tangerang city

Domain: https://sakila.tangerangsetankota.go.id

B. South Tangerang Regional Revenue Monitoring Application.

Domain:

http://103.219.112.114/retribution\_bapenda/login

C. Financial planning and management information system.

Domain: local public IP (URL is not published for reasons of data confidentiality)

IT support web developer

## **EKASAKTI OF UNIVERSITY (APRL 2017 - 2019)**

Develop information systems needed for academic and educational foundations

Manage campus alumni database and financial registration integrated with banking payments Participate and participate in campus events that are directly related to higher education information systems Make documentation of standard seven campus accreditation forms regarding information systems

Maintenance and monitoring of application servers so that they are monitored smoothly without any problems campus internet installation and configuration, including cabling and network infrastructure Provide tutorials on using applications that have been developed for users directly

Make a questionnaire to assess the satisfaction and effectiveness of the implementation of information systems in the campus environment

## Completed application project

A. University website

Domain http://unespadang.ac.id

B. Academic Siakad of the university

Domain http://siakad.unespadang.ac.id

C. Staffing system (Simpeng)

Domain: http://simpeg.unespadang.ac.id

D. New student admission system (PMB)

Domain: http://pendaftaran.unespadang.ac.id

E. Faculty of website

The faculty website application was created to increase promotions and information that is easy and cheap and can be accessed by internet users and students, with a domain address

- A. http://fkip.unespadang.ac.id (Faculty of Education)
- B. http://fekon.unespadang.ac.id (Faculty of Economics)
- C. http://fhum.unespadang.ac.id (Faculty of Law)
- D. http://faperta.unespadang.ac.id (Faculty of Agriculture)
- E. http://ft.unespadang.ac.id (Faculty of Engineering)
- F. http://sastra.unespadang.ac.id (Faculty of Letters)
- G. http://fisipol.unespadang.ac.id (Faculty of Social and Political Science)

## **CERTIFICATE**

- Bimbingan tekniks indeks keamanan informasi (KAMI), Padang By Badan Cyber dan Sandi Negara (BSSN) (2019)
- International Conference on Global Education (ICGE), Padang panjang (2019)
- Assessment for React Basic By HackerRank (2021)
- Assessment for Sql Intermediate By HackerRank (2021)
- Assessment for Python Basic By HackerRank (2021)
- Ubuntu Sysadmin Online Course (2020)
- Amazone Webservice Training and certification (AWS), By Amazone Webservice (2020)